Pepito Perez

CONTACT DETAILS

⋈ Paris area, France

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary researcher with 10+ years of experience at the intersection of biodiversity, public health, and environmental science. Expert in synthesising and communicating complex research findings to scientists, policymakers, and broader audiences. Adept at managing and organising international events. Strong skills in scientific synthesis, data visualisation, and collaborative leadership across Europe, the Americas, and international consortia (e.g., WHO, GAVI, NSF, VIMC).

SKILLS

- Leadership of international research projects and publications (e.g. VIMC, NSF-funded)
- Experienced in delivering presentations and writing reports to diverse audiences, including scientists, policy makers, and the general public.
- Vast experience working with international teams.
- Experience with bilateral and international cooperation (latinamerica and the United Kingdom).
- Great ability to synthesise complex data into accessible insights.
- Proactive and well-organized, with strong prioritization skills and a collaborative team spirit.
- Multilingual (Native in Spanish, professional competence in English and intermediate level in French/Italian).
- Tools: R, Python, Git, Excel, LaTeX, Office Suite

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH CONSULTANT (FREELANCE) Global/Remote

2022- now

- Supported policy-making institutions in assessing the potential for harmonizing and integrating vaccine impact estimates across platforms.
- Communicate findings through reports with global health stakeholders (VIMC, GAVI and BMGF).

RESEARCH CONSULTANT AND RESEARCH ASSOCIATE Imperial College London, UK

2019-2022

- Colaborated with a multidisciplinary team of researchers, technical experts, policy-oriented organisations, and project manager to deliver research and policy-driven reports.
- Ensured robust and policy-relevant outputs for decision-making in global health and produced regular technical reports to inform stakeholders and support evidence-based vaccine investment and advocacy.
- Drafted regular briefing notes and reports informing strategic investment decisions for global vaccination programs.
- Colaborated with Colombian researchers to understand the spread and early evolutionary history of SARS-CoV-2 in Colombia.

NSF POSTDOCTORAL ASSOCIATE Kenyon College, OH, USA

2017-2019

- Led research on plant biodiversity across biomes in the Americas, integrating phylogenetic and ecological data.
- Co-developed and taught an international module on "Global Ecology and Biogeography."
- Collaborated with Brazilian researchers on biome evolution. PI: Prof. Andrew Kerkhoff and Prof. Brian J. Enquist

LECTURER AND DEMONSTRATOR

2013-2017

Natural History Museum Imperial College London, UK

- Coordinated field-based data collection and analysis between Colombian researchers and UK institutions.
- Contributed to high-level scientific diplomacy, presenting biodiversity findings to political leaders including the Colombian president, ministers and HRH Prince Charles.

EDUCATION

Рн.D. in Life Science Imperial College London, UK.

2013-2017

 \diamond Thesis: Plant Macroevolution and biodiversity responses to land-use change.

M.RES. WITH DISTINCTION in Biodiversity, Informatics and Genomics *Imperial College London*, UK. **2012–2013**

♦ Thesis: Effects of land use on local biodiversity in Colombia.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY. 1st-class honours. *Universidad Industrial de Santander, Colombia.* **2004–2010**

SELECTED PROJECTS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Managed the weekly delivery of high-level reports to stakeholders (WHO, GAVI, BMGF), meeting strict deadlines.
- Participated and help organising international working meetings, coordinated multi-country datasets, and supported framework agreement development.
- Managed data acquisition and international communication for biodiversity monitoring initiatives between Colombian and european researchers ensuring bilateral cooperation (e.g., the PREDICTS).
- 30+ peer-reviewed articles in Lancet, Nature, eLife, Vaccine (see https://susyelo.github.io/publications.html).
- Awarded Outstanding Paper by Young Investigator (JSE, 2022).